[
  {
    Question:
      "What command is used to display the current date and time in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) date", "b) time", "c) datetime", "d) clock", "e) now"],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) date",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which command is used to list all files in a directory, including hidden files?",
    Answers: ["a) ls -l", "b) ls -a", "c) ls -h", "d) ls -s", "e) ls -d"],
    "Correct-Answer": "b) ls -a",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is the default shell in most Linux distributions?",
    Answers: ["a) Bash", "b) Zsh", "c) Fish", "d) Csh", "e) Dash"],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) Bash",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which command is used to display the manual page for a specific command in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) help", "b) man", "c) info", "d) manual", "e) helpme"],
    "Correct-Answer": "b) man",
  },
  {
    Question: "What command is used to create a new directory in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) make", "b) dir", "c) newdir", "d) mkdir", "e) mkd"],
    "Correct-Answer": "d) mkdir",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which command is used to copy files and directories in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) cp", "b) mv", "c) copy", "d) move", "e) duplicate"],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) cp",
  },
  {
    Question: "What command is used to change file permissions in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) chmod", "b) chperm", "c) permchange", "d) chown", "e) perm"],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) chmod",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which command is used to find files and directories in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) find", "b) search", "c) locate", "d) grep", "e) seek"],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) find",
  },
  {
    Question: "What command is used to remove files and directories in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) remove", "b) delete", "c) rm", "d) del", "e) erase"],
    "Correct-Answer": "c) rm",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which command is used to display the contents of a file in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) cat", "b) display", "c) show", "d) view", "e) read"],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) cat",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "What is the command used to search for text within files in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) search", "b) grep", "c) find", "d) locate", "e) textsearch"],
    "Correct-Answer": "b) grep",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which command is used to compress files and directories in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) compress", "b) tar", "c) zip", "d) gzip", "e) pack"],
    "Correct-Answer": "d) gzip",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "What is the command used to extract files from a compressed archive in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) unzip", "b) extract", "c) untar", "d) gunzip", "e) unpack"],
    "Correct-Answer": "d) gunzip",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which command is used to display the process status in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) ps", "b) status", "c) process", "d) pstree", "e) top"],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) ps",
  },
  {
    Question: "What command is used to terminate a running process in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) stop", "b) kill", "c) end", "d) terminate", "e) halt"],
    "Correct-Answer": "b) kill",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which command is used to schedule tasks to run periodically in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) cron",
      "b) scheduler",
      "c) tasker",
      "d) crontab",
      "e) schedule",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "d) crontab",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "What is the command used to display system information in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) info",
      "b) sysinfo",
      "c) uname",
      "d) systeminfo",
      "e) system",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "c) uname",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which command is used to shut down or reboot the system in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) shutdown",
      "b) reboot",
      "c) halt",
      "d) poweroff",
      "e) restart",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) shutdown",
  },
  {
    Question: "What command is used to change user password in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) passwd",
      "b) passchange",
      "c) changepwd",
      "d) userpasswd",
      "e) userpassword",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) passwd",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which command is used to display disk usage in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) df", "b) du", "c) diskusage", "d) diskinfo", "e) diskspace"],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) df",
  },
  {
    Question: "What command is used to display network configuration in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) netconfig",
      "b) ifconfig",
      "c) network",
      "d) netinfo",
      "e) config",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "b) ifconfig",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which command is used to display active network connections in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) netstat",
      "b) network",
      "c) netconnections",
      "d) connections",
      "e) activeconnections",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) netstat",
  },
  {
    Question: "What command is used to set up a static IP address in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) staticip",
      "b) ipconfig",
      "c) ifconfig",
      "d) setip",
      "e) static",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "c) ifconfig",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which command is used to configure the hostname in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) hostname",
      "b) hostconfig",
      "c) sethostname",
      "d) nameconfig",
      "e) confighost",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) hostname",
  },
  {
    Question: "What command is used to manage users in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) user",
      "b) manageuser",
      "c) usermod",
      "d) usermanage",
      "e) manage",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) user",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which command is used to add a new user in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) adduser",
      "b) newuser",
      "c) useradd",
      "d) createuser",
      "e) usernew",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "c) useradd",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is the command used to delete a user in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) deluser",
      "b) removeuser",
      "c) userdel",
      "d) deleteuser",
      "e) userremove",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "c) userdel",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which command is used to change the group of a file in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) changegroup",
      "b) groupchange",
      "c) chgrp",
      "d) changefilegroup",
      "e) filegroupchange",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "c) chgrp",
  },
  {
    Question: "What command is used to create a symbolic link in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) symlnk",
      "b) symlink",
      "c) createlink",
      "d) ln -s",
      "e) link",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "d) ln -s",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which command is used to display the contents of a compressed file in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) cat", "b) view", "c) less", "d) zcat", "e) read"],
    "Correct-Answer": "d) zcat",
  },
  {
    Question: "What command is used to install new software packages in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) installpkg",
      "b) pkginstall",
      "c) apt-get install",
      "d) yum install",
      "e) softwareinstall",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "c) apt-get install",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which command is used to update the package database in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) updatedb",
      "b) updb",
      "c) apt-get update",
      "d) yum update",
      "e) pkgupdate",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "c) apt-get update",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "What is the command used to uninstall software packages in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) uninstallpkg",
      "b) pkguninstall",
      "c) apt-get remove",
      "d) yum remove",
      "e) softwareuninstall",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "c) apt-get remove",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which command is used to search for files containing a specific text string in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) grep", "b) find", "c) search", "d) locate", "e) textsearch"],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) grep",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is the command used to change file ownership in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) chown",
      "b) ownfile",
      "c) changeowner",
      "d) fileown",
      "e) ownerchange",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) chown",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which command is used to change file permissions in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) chmod", "b) chperm", "c) permchange", "d) chown", "e) perm"],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) chmod",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "What command is used to display the last few lines of a file in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) last", "b) tail", "c) head", "d) cat", "e) read"],
    "Correct-Answer": "b) tail",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which command is used to display the first few lines of a file in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) top", "b) head", "c) tail", "d) first", "e) cat"],
    "Correct-Answer": "b) head",
  },
  {
    Question: "What command is used to rename files and directories in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) ren", "b) rename", "c) mv", "d) move", "e) filemove"],
    "Correct-Answer": "c) mv",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which command is used to create a new file in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) touch",
      "b) newfile",
      "c) createnew",
      "d) mkfile",
      "e) filecreate",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) touch",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "What command is used to view the contents of a directory in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) viewdir", "b) dir", "c) ls", "d) list", "e) showdir"],
    "Correct-Answer": "c) ls",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which command is used to display the disk space usage of a file or directory in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) space", "b) du", "c) diskspace", "d) df", "e) diskusage"],
    "Correct-Answer": "b) du",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "What is the command used to change the current user's password in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) chpass",
      "b) userpasswd",
      "c) changepass",
      "d) passwd",
      "e) passchange",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "d) passwd",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which command is used to display the manual page for a specific command in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) help", "b) man", "c) info", "d) manual", "e) helpme"],
    "Correct-Answer": "b) man",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is the command used to create a new directory in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) make", "b) dir", "c) newdir", "d) mkdir", "e) mkd"],
    "Correct-Answer": "d) mkdir",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which command is used to copy files and directories in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) cp", "b) mv", "c) copy", "d) move", "e) duplicate"],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) cp",
  },
  {
    Question: "What command is used to remove files and directories in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) remove", "b) delete", "c) rm", "d) del", "e) erase"],
    "Correct-Answer": "c) rm",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which command is used to display the contents of a file in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) cat", "b) display", "c) show", "d) view", "e) read"],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) cat",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "What is the command used to search for text within files in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) search", "b) grep", "c) find", "d) locate", "e) textsearch"],
    "Correct-Answer": "b) grep",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which command is used to compress files and directories in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) compress", "b) tar", "c) zip", "d) gzip", "e) pack"],
    "Correct-Answer": "d) gzip",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "What is the command used to extract files from a compressed archive in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) unzip", "b) extract", "c) untar", "d) gunzip", "e) unpack"],
    "Correct-Answer": "d) gunzip",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which command is used to display the process status in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) ps", "b) status", "c) process", "d) pstree", "e) top"],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) ps",
  },
  {
    Question: "What command is used to terminate a running process in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) stop", "b) kill", "c) end", "d) terminate", "e) halt"],
    "Correct-Answer": "b) kill",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which command is used to schedule tasks to run periodically in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) cron",
      "b) scheduler",
      "c) tasker",
      "d) crontab",
      "e) schedule",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "d) crontab",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "What is the command used to display system information in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) info",
      "b) sysinfo",
      "c) uname",
      "d) systeminfo",
      "e) system",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "c) uname",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which command is used to shut down or reboot the system in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) shutdown",
      "b) reboot",
      "c) halt",
      "d) poweroff",
      "e) restart",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) shutdown",
  },
  {
    Question: "What command is used to change user password in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) passwd",
      "b) passchange",
      "c) changepwd",
      "d) userpasswd",
      "e) userpassword",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) passwd",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which command is used to display disk usage in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) df", "b) du", "c) diskusage", "d) diskinfo", "e) diskspace"],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) df",
  },
  {
    Question: "What command is used to display network configuration in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) netconfig",
      "b) ifconfig",
      "c) network",
      "d) netinfo",
      "e) config",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "b) ifconfig",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which command is used to display active network connections in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) netstat",
      "b) network",
      "c) netconnections",
      "d) connections",
      "e) activeconnections",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) netstat",
  },
  {
    Question: "What command is used to set up a static IP address in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) staticip",
      "b) ipconfig",
      "c) ifconfig",
      "d) setip",
      "e) static",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "c) ifconfig",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which command is used to configure the hostname in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) hostname",
      "b) hostconfig",
      "c) sethostname",
      "d) nameconfig",
      "e) confighost",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) hostname",
  },
  {
    Question: "What command is used to manage users in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) user",
      "b) manageuser",
      "c) usermod",
      "d) usermanage",
      "e) manage",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) user",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which command is used to add a new user in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) adduser",
      "b) newuser",
      "c) useradd",
      "d) createuser",
      "e) usernew",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "c) useradd",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is the command used to delete a user in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) deluser",
      "b) removeuser",
      "c) userdel",
      "d) deleteuser",
      "e) userremove",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "c) userdel",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which command is used to change the group of a file in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) changegroup",
      "b) groupchange",
      "c) chgrp",
      "d) changefilegroup",
      "e) filegroupchange",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "c) chgrp",
  },
  {
    Question: "What command is used to create a symbolic link in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) symlnk",
      "b) symlink",
      "c) createlink",
      "d) ln -s",
      "e) link",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "d) ln -s",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which command is used to display the contents of a compressed file in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) cat", "b) view", "c) less", "d) zcat", "e) read"],
    "Correct-Answer": "d) zcat",
  },
  {
    Question: "What command is used to install new software packages in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) installpkg",
      "b) pkginstall",
      "c) apt-get install",
      "d) yum install",
      "e) softwareinstall",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "c) apt-get install",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which command is used to update the package database in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) updatedb",
      "b) updb",
      "c) apt-get update",
      "d) yum update",
      "e) pkgupdate",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "c) apt-get update",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "What is the command used to uninstall software packages in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) uninstallpkg",
      "b) pkguninstall",
      "c) apt-get remove",
      "d) yum remove",
      "e) softwareuninstall",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "c) apt-get remove",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which command is used to search for files containing a specific text string in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) grep", "b) find", "c) search", "d) locate", "e) textsearch"],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) grep",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is the command used to change file ownership in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) chown",
      "b) ownfile",
      "c) changeowner",
      "d) fileown",
      "e) ownerchange",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) chown",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which command is used to change file permissions in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) chmod", "b) chperm", "c) permchange", "d) chown", "e) perm"],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) chmod",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "What command is used to display the last few lines of a file in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) last", "b) tail", "c) head", "d) cat", "e) read"],
    "Correct-Answer": "b) tail",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which command is used to display the first few lines of a file in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) top", "b) head", "c) tail", "d) first", "e) cat"],
    "Correct-Answer": "b) head",
  },
  {
    Question: "What command is used to rename files and directories in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) ren", "b) rename", "c) mv", "d) move", "e) filemove"],
    "Correct-Answer": "c) mv",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which command is used to create a new file in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) touch",
      "b) newfile",
      "c) createnew",
      "d) mkfile",
      "e) filecreate",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) touch",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "What command is used to view the contents of a directory in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) viewdir", "b) dir", "c) ls", "d) list", "e) showdir"],
    "Correct-Answer": "c) ls",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which command is used to display the disk space usage of a file or directory in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) space", "b) du", "c) diskspace", "d) df", "e) diskusage"],
    "Correct-Answer": "b) du",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "What is the command used to change the current user's password in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) chpass",
      "b) userpasswd",
      "c) changepass",
      "d) passwd",
      "e) passchange",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "d) passwd",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which command is used to display the manual page for a specific command in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) help", "b) man", "c) info", "d) manual", "e) helpme"],
    "Correct-Answer": "b) man",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is the command used to create a new directory in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) make", "b) dir", "c) newdir", "d) mkdir", "e) mkd"],
    "Correct-Answer": "d) mkdir",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which command is used to copy files and directories in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) cp", "b) mv", "c) copy", "d) move", "e) duplicate"],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) cp",
  },
  {
    Question: "What command is used to remove files and directories in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) remove", "b) delete", "c) rm", "d) del", "e) erase"],
    "Correct-Answer": "c) rm",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which command is used to display the contents of a file in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) cat", "b) display", "c) show", "d) view", "e) read"],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) cat",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "What is the command used to search for text within files in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) search", "b) grep", "c) find", "d) locate", "e) textsearch"],
    "Correct-Answer": "b) grep",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which command is used to compress files and directories in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) compress", "b) tar", "c) zip", "d) gzip", "e) pack"],
    "Correct-Answer": "d) gzip",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "What is the command used to extract files from a compressed archive in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) unzip", "b) extract", "c) untar", "d) gunzip", "e) unpack"],
    "Correct-Answer": "d) gunzip",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which command is used to display the process status in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) ps", "b) status", "c) process", "d) pstree", "e) top"],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) ps",
  },
  {
    Question: "What command is used to terminate a running process in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) stop", "b) kill", "c) end", "d) terminate", "e) halt"],
    "Correct-Answer": "b) kill",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which command is used to schedule tasks to run periodically in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) cron",
      "b) scheduler",
      "c) tasker",
      "d) crontab",
      "e) schedule",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "d) crontab",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "What is the command used to display system information in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) info",
      "b) sysinfo",
      "c) uname",
      "d) systeminfo",
      "e) system",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "c) uname",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which command is used to shut down or reboot the system in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) shutdown",
      "b) reboot",
      "c) halt",
      "d) poweroff",
      "e) restart",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) shutdown",
  },
  {
    Question: "What command is used to change user password in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) passwd",
      "b) passchange",
      "c) changepwd",
      "d) userpasswd",
      "e) userpassword",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) passwd",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which command is used to display disk usage in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) df", "b) du", "c) diskusage", "d) diskinfo", "e) diskspace"],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) df",
  },
  {
    Question: "What command is used to display network configuration in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) netconfig",
      "b) ifconfig",
      "c) network",
      "d) netinfo",
      "e) config",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "b) ifconfig",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which command is used to display active network connections in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) netstat",
      "b) network",
      "c) netconnections",
      "d) connections",
      "e) activeconnections",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) netstat",
  },
  {
    Question: "What command is used to set up a static IP address in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) staticip",
      "b) ipconfig",
      "c) ifconfig",
      "d) setip",
      "e) static",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "c) ifconfig",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which command is used to configure the hostname in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) hostname",
      "b) hostconfig",
      "c) sethostname",
      "d) nameconfig",
      "e) confighost",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) hostname",
  },
  {
    Question: "What command is used to manage users in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) user",
      "b) manageuser",
      "c) usermod",
      "d) usermanage",
      "e) manage",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) user",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which command is used to add a new user in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) adduser",
      "b) newuser",
      "c) useradd",
      "d) createuser",
      "e) usernew",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "c) useradd",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is the command used to delete a user in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) deluser",
      "b) removeuser",
      "c) userdel",
      "d) deleteuser",
      "e) userremove",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "c) userdel",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which command is used to change the group of a file in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) changegroup",
      "b) groupchange",
      "c) chgrp",
      "d) changefilegroup",
      "e) filegroupchange",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "c) chgrp",
  },
  {
    Question: "What command is used to create a symbolic link in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) symlnk",
      "b) symlink",
      "c) createlink",
      "d) ln -s",
      "e) link",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "d) ln -s",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which command is used to display the contents of a compressed file in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) cat", "b) view", "c) less", "d) zcat", "e) read"],
    "Correct-Answer": "d) zcat",
  },
  {
    Question: "What command is used to install new software packages in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) installpkg",
      "b) pkginstall",
      "c) apt-get install",
      "d) yum install",
      "e) softwareinstall",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "c) apt-get install",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which command is used to update the package database in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) updatedb",
      "b) updb",
      "c) apt-get update",
      "d) yum update",
      "e) pkgupdate",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "c) apt-get update",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "What is the command used to uninstall software packages in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) uninstallpkg",
      "b) pkguninstall",
      "c) apt-get remove",
      "d) yum remove",
      "e) softwareuninstall",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "c) apt-get remove",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which command is used to search for files containing a specific text string in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) grep", "b) find", "c) search", "d) locate", "e) textsearch"],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) grep",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is the command used to change file ownership in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) chown",
      "b) ownfile",
      "c) changeowner",
      "d) fileown",
      "e) ownerchange",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) chown",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which command is used to change file permissions in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) chmod", "b) chperm", "c) permchange", "d) chown", "e) perm"],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) chmod",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "What command is used to display the last few lines of a file in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) last", "b) tail", "c) head", "d) cat", "e) read"],
    "Correct-Answer": "b) tail",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which command is used to display the first few lines of a file in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) top", "b) head", "c) tail", "d) first", "e) cat"],
    "Correct-Answer": "b) head",
  },
  {
    Question: "What command is used to rename files and directories in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) ren", "b) rename", "c) mv", "d) move", "e) filemove"],
    "Correct-Answer": "c) mv",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which command is used to create a new file in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) touch",
      "b) newfile",
      "c) createnew",
      "d) mkfile",
      "e) filecreate",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) touch",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "What command is used to view the contents of a directory in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) viewdir", "b) dir", "c) ls", "d) list", "e) showdir"],
    "Correct-Answer": "c) ls",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which command is used to display the disk space usage of a file or directory in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) space", "b) du", "c) diskspace", "d) df", "e) diskusage"],
    "Correct-Answer": "b) du",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "What is the command used to change the current user's password in Linux?",
    Answers: [
      "a) chpass",
      "b) userpasswd",
      "c) changepass",
      "d) passwd",
      "e) passchange",
    ],
    "Correct-Answer": "d) passwd",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which command is used to display the manual page for a specific command in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) help", "b) man", "c) info", "d) manual", "e) helpme"],
    "Correct-Answer": "b) man",
  },
  {
    Question: "What is the command used to create a new directory in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) make", "b) dir", "c) newdir", "d) mkdir", "e) mkd"],
    "Correct-Answer": "d) mkdir",
  },
  {
    Question: "Which command is used to copy files and directories in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) cp", "b) mv", "c) copy", "d) move", "e) duplicate"],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) cp",
  },
  {
    Question: "What command is used to remove files and directories in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) remove", "b) delete", "c) rm", "d) del", "e) erase"],
    "Correct-Answer": "c) rm",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which command is used to display the contents of a file in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) cat", "b) display", "c) show", "d) view", "e) read"],
    "Correct-Answer": "a) cat",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "What is the command used to search for text within files in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) search", "b) grep", "c) find", "d) locate", "e) textsearch"],
    "Correct-Answer": "b) grep",
  },
  {
    Question:
      "Which command is used to compress files and directories in Linux?",
    Answers: ["a) compress", "b) tar", "c) zip", "d) gzip", "e) pack"],
    "Correct-Answer": "d) gzip",
  },
];
